Sorry to interrupt.
不好意思二位华少爷
But the word
其实这个皮带的
"Shunchang"
皮带头上
inside the belt
烙印着顺昌两个字
has served as conclusive evidence.
就已经是铁证了
I explained this
上次庭审的时候
during the last trial.
我已经解释过了
Have you
难道二位
forgotten?
忘了吗
We've obtained
皮带的收据
the receipt.
我们弄到手了
It bears your mother's
上面有你母亲的
signature.
亲笔签名
Take a close look.
你仔细辨认一下
Let me see.
来 我看看
Excuse me.
佟参谋长
Thanks.
好
This signature
这个签名啊
could also be forged.
它也可以是伪造的
I'm skeptical
我很怀疑
about the authenticity of the receipt.
这张收据的真实性
After all, my mother
毕竟我母亲
has no recollection of it.
是一点儿印象都没有
She wouldn't lie, would she?
我母亲总不会撒谎吧
She only remembers ordering
她只记得在这家店里
a... pendant for a necklace
定制过那个那个
from this store.
项链的吊坠
How do you intend to prove it then?
您到底想怎么证明呢
After all,
毕竟
we can't
我们不可能
keep doing this forever.
无休无止地纠缠下去
Well,
这样吧
you know
你不是知道
I had Mr. Li
我把李老板
come over from Nanjing.
从南京请过来了吗
Let him speak.
让他说
If he can personally confirm
让他亲口承认
that this belt
这条皮带
was custom-made
是我母亲
in his shop by my mother,
在他店里面定做的
I'll drop the matter.
我就不再追究这件事情
Okay?
好吧
Bring in Mr. Li.
请李老板
Sir, can you fix it?
师傅能修好吧
I'm just a driver,
我只是个司机
not a mechanic.
不会修车
It's hard to say.
这玩意儿不好说
Probably
估计
have to wait for the repair service.
得等修车公司的人来了
Coming through!
让一让 让一让
Chief.
参谋长
Mr. Li,
李老板
the reason you're here today
今天请你到这儿来呢
is to explain
就是让你当庭
to everyone
向我们各位长官
about
解释一下
this belt
关于这条皮带
and the receipt
以及这个收据的
in question.
来龙去脉
Please.
请
Okay.
好
This receipt
这个收据
was made when Mrs. Hua
是华夫人在我们店里
purchased this belt at our store.
买这条皮带的收据
As the wife of the Undersecretary
华夫人家老爷啊
of the Ministry of Military Affairs,
是军政部的次长
she often brings
华夫人经常
high-society ladies
带一些阔太太
to shop at our store.
到我店来买东西
This belt wasn't cheap.
这个皮带它可不便宜啊
This... leather...
这个这 这个皮子
was imported.
是进口的
I personally
这皮带扣呢
crafted the buckle.
还是我亲自打造的呢
Mrs. Hua said
当时华夫人说
it's custom-made
是给他们家二公子
for her second son.
定做的
Oh,
对了
for the gentleman right there.
就是这位公子
I've seen him in photos.
我在照片上见过他
Mr. Li,
李老板
nice to meet you again.
咱们又见面了
What you said
你说的话
will affect my brother's life.
关乎我弟弟的生死
Then be careful
所以你说话
with your words!
给我小心点儿
Tell me,
我问你
is everything you've
你刚才说的话
just said true?
都是真的吗
Sure. All of it.
是真的 都是真的
I swear to heaven.
我冲天发誓都是真的
Make way!
让一让
Move!
让
Captain! Here!
队长 这里这里
Captain!
队长
Finally.
可算来了
Captain, are you alright?
队长 你没事吧
Captain, you've worked hard.
快快 队长辛苦了
Hurry up! Move!
走 快走 走
Quick!
快
Stop!
站住站住
State your purpose.
你们干什么的
We're bringing a witness
我们带证人进去
for the tribunal.
会审的证人
The investigation team
侦查队没说
didn't notify us.
今天有新证人来
An important witness.
这是重要证人
Maybe
那个
you should go and check?
要 要不你们进去问问
If there's a delay,
这耽误了
nobody wants that responsibility,
咱 咱谁也担不起
right?
是不是
Please check for us.
麻烦你们问一下吧
You all wait here.
你们在这里等着
Stay here.
看好了
Yes, sir.
是
Cigarette?
来 辛苦 来抽颗烟
No, thanks.
不用了
Where are you from?
兄弟哪儿人呢
The Northeast.
东北的
Wow,
我天
that's great!
东北的 东北好啊
Don't move!
别动 别动
Stop! Stop!
站住 站住
Miss Luo, go inside!
骆警官你先进去
Stop!
站住
You can't go in!
你们不能进去
Stop! Or I'll shoot!
站住 再跑我就开枪了
No!
别开枪
This is the witness
这是侍从室
for Mr. Hua!
华秘书的证人
Calm down!
我看你们谁敢开枪
Hold it right there!
站住 站住
Stop!
站住
Honestly, I agree with Hua Zhen.
其实我同意华桢的说法
I'm serious.
真的 华秘书
At this point,
都到了这个地步
the matter of the belt
皮带不皮带的
is no longer important.
已经不重要了
So what if it's his?
是他的皮带又怎样
He just wanna save a man
他不知道对方是共产党
who was an unexpected communist
华二少心有慈悲
out of sympathy.
他想救人一命
Unfortunately,
可惜呀
the document for Xiang Yuansheng
那个向远生的身份证明
has thoroughly
能够彻头彻尾地证明
and definitively proved
他就是共产党
that
那
Hua Zhen
才是证明华桢
is also a communist!
是共产党的铁证
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
I think this is
我觉得这件事情
all we can do for now.
可能只能这样了
We can't
我们毕竟
keep dragging this out.
不能长时间纠缠下去
Mr. Hua!
华秘书
Quiet! What are you doing?
闭嘴 干什么呢
The witness has arrived!
华秘书 证人到了
Mr. Hua!
华秘书
The witness is here!
华秘书 你证人到了
Chief Tong, Commander Yang,
佟参谋长 杨司令
my witness has arrived.
我的证人到了
Xiang Yuan Sheng.
向远生
We're not too late, are we?
我们没来晚吧
Not at all. Just in time.
没来晚 时间刚好
Find the landlady
给我把
who provided us tips
提供线索那个房东太太
in Guangzhou,
解决掉
and keep her silenced permanently.
我要她永远闭嘴
Sorry,
杨司令 佟参谋长
but shall we continue?
咱们可以继续了吗
Yuansheng!
远生
The witness will stay.
证人留下
Everyone else may leave.
无关人员离开法庭
Let's continue.
我们继续
Yuansheng,
远生
we'll wait for you outside!
我们在外面等你啊
Wait outside. Don't worry.
你先出去等吧 放心
Mrs. Xu, please.
徐太太
I couldn't just let these 3 days
我肯定不能白白浪费
be a waste.
大家这三天的时间呀
Apart from Mr. Li,
除了李老板
I also invited Mrs. Xu.
我还请来了徐太太
She is the landlady
她就是魏队长说的
of the apartment in Guangzhou
广州公寓的那个
Captain Wei mentioned.
女房东
How is it possible?
你怎么做到的
She's still in Guangzhou yesterday...
她昨天还在广州
How could she
怎么可能
get from Guangzhou
从广州这么快
to Shanghai so quickly?
就到了上海
Because in your mind,
因为在你的概念里
there's only boats and trains.
只有轮船 火车
A military plane is available for us!
我们可以坐军用飞机啊
She left this morning,
早上出发
just in time.
时间刚刚好
Mrs. Xu,
徐太太
now you can talk
关于那四本证件
about the four documents.
现在可以说了
Sir,
长官
here's the situation.
事情是这样的
Mr. Zhang is a distant relative of mine.
老张是我远房亲戚
He rented a room from me
他之前跟我租了房子
and paid the rent,
给了我房租之后
but nobody ever moved in.
但是一直都没人来住
My son is getting married,
我儿子要结婚
and I wanna take the house back
我就想把房子收回来
for him.
给我儿子做婚房
I found the documents
证件是我
while cleaning out
在收拾行李的时候
the luggage.
发现的
I put them
我就放在
in the suitcase,
他的行李包里了
all four of them.
一共有四本
Be responsible with what you say.
说话要负责任
Mrs. Xu,
徐太太
why didn't you report this
我去广州的时候
when I was in Guangzhou?
你怎么不汇报这些呢
You
先生
didn't ask me about it.
您当时也没问我呀
Take a look.
看看吧
Is that them?
是这四本吗
Yes...
是这个
Wait, this isn't right...
不对啊
Uh...
这个
The person
这个人
I remember
跟之前那个不一样
had a slightly
我记得那个人的脸
broader face,
是稍微宽一点儿的
totally different
跟这个人长得
from this one.
完全不一样啊
Is it this man?
是这个人吗
Yes, correct!
是他是他
Definitely him!
我记得就是他
Good.
好
Captain Wei,
魏队长
how do you explain this now?
你现在怎么解释
Explain?
怎么解释
You seem to suspect
华秘书的意思
that our investigation team
无非是说我们侦查队
is fabricating evidence.
在弄虚作假呗
Wei Daiqing!
魏岱擎
I have every reason to believe
我现在完全有理由相信
that what you've done
你所做的这一切
is purposed to frame my brother!
就是为了诬陷我弟弟
Frame?
诬陷你弟弟
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
a man of your status
您这么大的人物
needn't stoop
完全没有必要
to such
跟我一个
low tactics with
小小的侦查队长
a mere
耍这些
investigation team captain.
下三滥的手段
This so-called new witness
你这个新冒出来的证人
is under your manipulation, innit?
是您的暗箱操作吧
Sir,
报告各位长官
just before the hearing today,
今天 在会审开始之前
I saw Mr. Hua
我还在金门饭店
meeting with
咖啡厅里
a witness in the café
看见了华秘书
of the Jinmen Hotel.
在会见证人
What deal was struck there
具体达成了什么交易
remains unknown.
那就不得而知了
Whom I meet
我见了什么人啊
is not important.
并不重要
What matters is the evidence.
重要的是那些证据
According to you,
按你说的
these documents
这四本证件
have been
你们侦查队
in your team's possession
在广州的公寓
since being taken
拿走之后
from the apartment,
就一直在你们那儿保管
right?
对吗
Correct.
对的
Well then,
好
I'd like to know
那我再请问你
how did the photo of He Youqing
这何友庆的照片
turn into
是怎么变成
my brother's?
我弟弟的照片
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
the investigation team has its protocols.
侦查队有侦查队的规矩
I assure all officials here,
我可以向各位长官保证
the documents I saw
当初我在广州寓所
in the apartment
看到的这四本证件
are exactly
当初是什么样子的
as they were!
现在还是什么样子
Not just I
侦查队不止我
handle the case alone,
一个人办案
all team members
华秘书
were there watching.
所有队员都跟着看着呢
I had no chance for any black box work!
我没有暗箱操作的空间
Who can testify to that?
谁能作证
I can.
我可以
Sir,
各位长官
I went to the apartment
那天确实是我和魏队长
with Captain Wei that day.
一起去的广州寓所
The documents we obtained then
在寓所看到的四本证件
were indeed the ones we have now.
确实就是这四本
However,
但是
Mr. Hua is also correct.
华秘书说得也没错
The photo
向远生的这本
for Xiang Yuansheng
证件照片
has indeed been changed.
确实被换过了
Gao Pingshun...
高平顺
Commander!
司令
Gao Pingshun has been sweetened!
高平顺被华秘书收买了
Wei Daiqing!
魏岱擎
You have the nerve!
你是真厉害呀
You have all officers of Shanghai
你让上海所有的官员
watching a drama with you!
陪着你看了一出儿戏
Jesus!
你呀
Commander!
司令
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
Yuansheng! Yuansheng!
远生  向警官
Yuansheng!
向警官
It's over.
没事儿了
Unlock him!
没事儿给我解开啊
Our efforts weren't in vain!
太好了 咱努力没白费
Indeed!
没白费
Come on, quick!
来来来 快快快
Captain will be so relieved
队长要知道你没事儿
to know you're safe!
肯定高兴
All thanks to him
全靠队长一个人
who pulled
用黄包车
the landlady here with a rickshaw!
把房东太太给拉过来的
Minmin was impressive too!
珉敏也厉害
Calling Mr. Hua
一进大厅
as soon as she entered the hall!
我就听到她喊华先生
Precisely!
对对对
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you all.
谢谢你们
Hongfa,
鸿发
let's take Yuansheng
咱一会儿
out for a bath later.
带向警官出去洗个澡
No problem!
没问题
Wash away the bad luck!
去去晦气
Right!
对
You must be hungry.
你一定没吃好
Later, go to my restaurant.
一会儿去我们家酒楼啊
I'll make sure you eat well!
我安排你使劲吃
Eat all you want!
使劲吃
Sure.
好
Family Hua is really something.
这华家可真厉害
Once Mr. Hua took a seat,
他哥往上一坐
no one dared to speak up.
谁敢说话
His is...
他哥哥是那个
Chief...
侍
Chief Aide.
侍秘书
I know he's an aide.
我知道是秘书
Keep it down.
行行 行了 小点儿声
Don't embarrass us here.
别在这儿丢人现眼
Me?
我丢人现眼
Listen. That's called
我告诉你 记住了啊
the Chief Aide
人家那叫
in the Office of Aides.
侍从室第一大秘书
Well, what does he do?
第一大秘书是干啥的
Come on.
你看完了又完了
You don't know that?
不知道了吧
Let me explain,
我给你们展开讲一下
The Chief Aide...
侍从室第一大秘书
is...
大秘书
Anyway, he's crucial
他 他就首先
to the Office of Aides.
离不开侍从室
And the Office is inseparable
聊到侍从室
from the National Government...
那就离不开国民政府
Officers from the Fourth Station?
是四所的警员吗
Yes.
是 是
He's an aide to the Chief Aide.
那个 大秘书的秘书
Mr. Hua wants to invite you
华秘书想邀请大家
to dine together at the Jinmen Hotel.
一起到金门饭店吃个饭
Jinmen Hotel?
金门饭店
That's a fancy place!
那大饭店 方便方便
Will Yuansheng come too?
向警官也来吗
He will.
他来
After the exoneration process
他办完无罪释放的
is
手续之后
finished.
就会过来
Oh,
对了
what about our Captain?
还有我们队长
He hasn't arrived yet.
队长还没进来
Rest assured,
您放心
Mr. Hua will
这个华秘书
make all well arranged.
都会安排好的
Alright then.
那行那行
I'll
那这样
take you there now.
我先送您几位过去
Okay.
好吧
Sure.
行行
Let's go.
走走
Minmin, get in.
珉敏上车
Let's move.
走走走
Miss Luo,
骆警官 快上车
follow us.
别愣着了
Minmin, hurry up.
珉敏 快点儿
Coming.
来了
Another thing,
对了
please pick up our director too.
还有我们所长接一下
Okay.
好
Captain Wei.
魏队长
don't you
你是不是
owe me something?
还欠我什么东西呢
You are too ambitious,
你的野心啊 太大了
but your foundation
但是你的本钱
is not solid.
少得可怜
Nice shoes.
新鞋不错
Liang,
哥
you contacted Gao Pingshun, right?
是你找的高平顺
He's been dissatisfied with Wei Daiqing.
他早都不满魏岱擎了
I just gave him a push.
我不过是顺水推舟
Won't he get into trouble
你让他出卖魏岱擎
for betraying Wei?
他不会有麻烦吗
I've arranged everything.
我已经安排好了
He wanna start a business in Hong Kong.
他想去香港做个生意
I've prepared
船票 钱
his boat ticket and money.
我都给他准备好了
He leaves tomorrow at noon.
明天中午就上船
Will the owner of the jewelry shop
那饰品店的老板呢
in trouble?
会有麻烦吗
He'll go back
他回南京
to run his shop in Nanjing.
继续开他的小店
No one will dare touch him there.
在南京没人敢动他
Hua Zhen,
华桢
I have to ask,
我倒是想问问你
this isn't your first fight
你这不是第一次
in Shanghai, is it?
在上海打架了吧
That wasn't a fight,
我那不是打架
but a one-sided beating.
只是单方面的揍了他
You seem to
我看你啊
forget all about the school regulations.
军校的校规你全都忘了
Go and say goodbye to him.
去跟他道个别吧
You
以后你们应该
may not meet again.
没有机会见面了
Are you alright?
没事了吧
I'm fine.
没事了
When do you plan to leave?
准备什么时候出发
The first train this afternoon.
下午第一趟火车
I thought you only
之前我一直以为
wasted a month
你留在上海
staying
查孟家凶杀案
in Shanghai
耽误的只是
for the murder case.
一个月的时间
Unexpectedly,
但没想到
you also risked your future.
你还赌上了自己的前途
Go back and be a good naval officer.
回去好好当你的海军
You belong to the sea.
你是心里装着大海的人
The airport is so far.
机场过来这么远
Didn't you think to call a taxi?
也不知道叫辆出租车
The car broke down.
车坏了我也没办法
I even had to hijack a rickshaw.
黄包车还是劫来的
Hurry and catch your train.
赶紧赶火车吧
I can't help if you're late.
再不走我也管不了了
If you
将来要是
can't make it in the navy,
在海军混不下去
come back to us.
随时回四所
I can help with that.
这个我能管
If that day ever comes,
如果真有那么一天
I'll be back.
我会回来的
Good.
好
Revert to your name
回去之后
when back in Nanjing,
换回之前的名字吧
do your best
老老实实回学校
in the school training
训练也好
or even fighting,
打仗也好
and forget what happened in Shanghai.
忘了在上海发生的事情
Anyway,
不管怎么样
we're each destined
我们终归是
for different paths.
两条路上的人
Captain Chen,
陈队长
thank you.
谢谢
Don't call me that.
别叫队长
Call me Chen Hao.
叫陈浩吧
Take care.
保重
Goodbye.
再见
I planned to
本来我想
treat your police friends to a meal,
请四所的警员们吃顿饭
but they
但是他们说
got suddenly called back
突然接到了要紧案子
to a case.
就都赶回去了
I wanna...
哥
say goodbye
我想去四所
to them in person.
跟他们道个别
There's no time now.
来不及了
Maybe
以后有机会
call them later.
打电话给他们吧
Also,
另外啊
you need to cut all ties
你也要跟上海的一切
with Shanghai.
都要划清界限
Do you know why
你知道为什么
Wei Daiqing
魏岱擎明知道
didn't do anything
高平顺反水
when betrayed by Gao Pingshun?
却又不敢说吗
Because
因为照片
he changed the photo himself.
是他自己贴上去的
Then,
那我再问你
how did
魏岱擎
a small team leader
一个侦查队小队长
have the guts
他哪儿来的底气
to investigate our family?
查咱们华家
Do you think he can do it himself?
你觉得他有这个本钱吗
And why
我又是为什么
didn't I pursue it further?
不再追究魏岱擎
Because if we
因为如果一直
kept digging,
再查下去的话
we'd uncover things we shouldn't.
就会查到不该查的东西
Our family
咱们华家
is closely tied to Family Kong,
和孔氏家族关系密切
which could easily make us a target.
难免会招人记恨
If something happens to you,
如果你出了问题
it will draw predators
就会有无数只饿狼
towards me and our father.
扑向我和爸爸
Honestly,
还有你
you should think more
你应该为家里
about the family.
多考虑考虑了
I've got one more thing to handle.
我还有点儿事儿
You go to the train station.
你先去火车站
I'll be there shortly.
我马上就到
Drive to the station
送他去火车站
and watch him get aboard.
看着他上车
Yes, sir.
是
Sir, all set.
先生 您的菜上齐了
Erbai,
哥
I bet this meal
你说这一顿饭
will cost us half a year's salary.
不得顶咱半年薪水啊
More than that.
不止
More?
不止啊
Dongbao,
冬宝
you're impressive today,
你今儿挺厉害
grabbing the man just like that.
咔就给人抱住
I grew up wrestling pigs.
我们从小抱猪抱习惯了
Grabbing him was just instinct.
咔给他抱住
Erbai was the real star,
还得是二白哥厉害
"No! Calm down!"
不许动 我看谁敢动
Right?
是不是哥
Tell me,
不是 哥
weren't you scared?
你当时不害怕吗
The gun was right on you.
那枪就抵着你
What if...?
这万一呢
I was sweating bullets.
捏把汗都
Thanks to
经验
experience and courage.
还有就是勇敢
Watch and learn.
你们就多学
But you all did
但是你们今天
very well today.
表现得非常好
We had some good teamwork.
咱们有点儿小默契
We deserve
为了自己
applause!
鼓掌
Don't eat now.
菜不动
But have a drink.
喝 喝他一杯酒
We kindly remind you
要上车的旅客
to take care of
抓紧时间了
all your belongings
拿好自己的随身物品
and watch your step.
小心脚下
Please check your ticket quickly
后面没有检票的快点
and get aboard.
准备上车
Hold on a second.
等一下
The train is about to leave.
二少爷 火车马上开了
Young Master!
二少爷
We don't have time,
车马上就要开了
please
二少爷
don't make this difficult.
您 您别为难我二少爷
Excuse me.
你好
I'm from the S.M.C.
我是军政部
of the Ministry of Military Affairs.
电雷学校的学员
May I
我有重要的事情
give an emergency call?
麻烦借用一下电话
♪After finishing one drink,♪
喝完了一杯
♪time for another.♪
再来一杯
Hello, the Fourth Station House.
喂 第四警察所左荣华
This is Xiang Yuansheng
喂 所长
speaking.
是我
Yuansheng?
小向啊
Sun Hongfa called
孙鸿发打电话说你
to say you're out safely!
平安出来了
Thank God!
好事儿
Is Luo Minmin there?
骆珉敏在吗
No, she isn't.
骆珉敏不在啊
She's now
和那几个臭小子
at the Jinmen Hotel.
去金门饭店了
I'm about to head there myself.
我这也准备着要去呢
Your brother invited us...
你哥哥请我们
He hung up?
挂了
Miss Luo, right?
骆小姐是吧
Yes.
对
Your call.
您的电话
Thank you.
谢谢
Hello, may I
喂 您好 我是骆珉敏
ask who's calling?
请问您找我
This is
是我
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
I'm at the train station now.
我现在在火车站
It's almost impossible
可能没有机会
to see everyone again.
跟大家见面了
Could you please
帮我跟他们
pass on my thanks?
说一声感谢吧
Sure,
好
I will relay your message.
我会替你转达的
I major in navigation science
我在电雷学校二期
at Class 3 of the S.M.C.
航海科三班
What?
什么
I'm
我说
at Class 3
我在江阴
of the S.M.C.
军政部电雷学校二期
in Jiangyin.
航海科三班
We can write to each other.
我们可以写信
A letter from Jiangyin to Shanghai
信从江阴到上海
only takes a week.
最快只需要一周的时间
I'll write to you.
我会给你写信的
The train to Nanjing
前往南京的旅客
is about to leave.
请抓紧上车
Please get aboard quickly.
马上就要发车了
Luo Minmin,
骆珉敏
did you hear that?
你听见了吗
I saw you being taken away,
我亲眼看到你被抓走
and interrogated
又亲眼看到你
in handcuffs
戴着手铐脚铐
and chains.
被审问
I know
我知道这次
you might not have come out.
很有可能你就出不来了
This is different
这和我们
from the cases we handled
在四所审的案子
at the Fourth Station.
都不一样
Maybe you don't care,
可能你不在乎
but I was really scared.
但是我是真的害怕
Should we keep in touch?
我们还应该再联系吗
What if something happens to you again?
如果你再出事怎么办
What if you get
如果你被关进去了
locked up
死掉了
and die?
怎么办
What should I do
如果下一次
if you are
你真的出不来了
not rescued
死掉了
next time?
我怎么办
Just remember
你只需要记住
that I'm Hua Zhen,
电雷学校二期
at Class 3 of the S.M.C.
航海科三班华桢
That's all that matters.
其他的一切都不重要
I will write to you.
我会给你写信的
Write back to me.
给我回信
Did you get that?
记住了吗
The train is about to leave!
马上就要发车了
Please hurry to board!
请旅客们抓紧上车
Young Master,
二少爷
we're running out of time.
来不及了
The train is about to leave.
马上就要开车了
Wait!
等会儿
Luo Minmin,
骆珉敏
answer me.
回答我
Okay,
好
I promise.
我记住了
It's the time
前往南京的旅客
for the train to Nanjing.
请抓紧上车
Thank you.
谢谢
Miss Luo,
骆小姐
I've gathered
我大致了解了一下
that you met
你们是在
during your police duties.
当警察的时候认识的
So, you've known
那也就是说
each other for no more than a month?
认识不超过一个月
Yes.
对
Actually,
其实
Xiang Yuansheng
向远生
saying we were in a relationship
说我们是恋人关系
was also a way
也是为了
to deal with the investigative team.
应付侦查队的人
I suspect
我想也不光是
it's not just that.
为了应付魏岱擎吧
Otherwise, why would you
不然你们怎么会
talk until midnight?
在四所聊到半夜呢
It's because
那是因为
he was leaving the next day.
他第二天要走了
So we talked late.
所以聊得晚了些
May I ask
那我能冒昧地问一句
what you discussed?
你们都聊了些什么吗
About the navy,
聊了海军
the reason why he chose to join it,
聊他为什么要当海军
the gap
聊了
between our fleet
我们的舰艇
and Japan's,
和日本舰艇的差距
the story
聊了
of me becoming a police officer,
我为什么要当警察
and family.
还有家人
Family?
家人
Yes.
对
He talked about his relationship
他说他的父亲
with his father,
和他的关系
and how it's completely different
和我和我爸爸的关系
from mine.
完全不一样
He sounded like a little boy
他说这些的时候
when he mentioned that.
就像一个小孩子
Since you've
既然你们已经
shared so much,
聊了这么多
I won't
那我也就
consider you an outsider.
不把你当外人了
Since you're
骆小姐
a police officer,
您是一位女警察
I respect that greatly.
我非常地尊重您
Out of respect,
也是出于尊重
I want to make things clear.
我要把事情讲清楚
It's the
现在是
holiday period of the S.M.C.
电雷学校的放假期间
After that,
假期结束之后
Hua Zhen will return
华桢就要回到学校
to continue his training.
去参加训练
Once at sea, he'll be gone for months,
一出海就是几个月
and after graduation,
而且毕了业之后啊
he will stay in Nanjing.
他会留在南京
He won't come back to Shanghai.
不会再来上海
That's his life plan.
因为这是他的人生规划
This isn't
所以这对您来说
fair to you.
很不公平
Do you understand?
你明白我的意思吗
Yes.
我明白
Let me add a bit more.
我再多说几句吧
Our family
我们的家庭啊
might seem
看起来比别人
more powerful than others,
多了几分权力
but it's mostly not by choice.
但是更多的是身不由己
If Hua Zhen gets into trouble,
如果华桢出了事情
we'll spare no expense to save him.
我们会不惜代价去救他
But he must also fulfill
但是他也要承担
his duties to the family.
对家庭的责任
For instance,
比如说
he's about to be engaged soon.
过一阵他就要订婚了
He didn't tell you, right?
华桢没有告诉你吧
He didn't intentionally conceal it from you,
不是因为他刻意隐瞒你
but he himself didn't know about it.
是因为他自己也不知道
That's what I mean by
这就是我跟你说的
not by choice.
身不由己
You've seen
他现在的处境
his situation.
你也看到了
His behavior here
自从他来了上海之后
is so weird.
他的行为变得很奇怪
He's going off track.
他在脱轨
That's why I need him
所以我要让他
to cut all ties
和上海的一切
with Shanghai
划清界限
because he can't be
因为他不可能
lucky every time.
每一次都这么幸运
Perhaps what I'm saying
也许我说的这些
may not persuade you,
对你来说都没有说服力
but you must care
但是他的人身安全
about his safety.
你一定是在乎的
So, for this reason,
所以为了他的安全
please sever your ties with him.
请骆小姐跟他断绝关系
Then he has no distractions.
不要让他有任何的牵绊
I've taken care of the bill
包厢里的账单
in the private room
我已经买过了
and
另外我还多付了
paid double.
一倍的价钱
Order whatever you like.
你们想吃什么随便点
I am in a hurry
我还要赶时间
to go to the train station.
现在要去火车站
I won't say thanks
我就不当面
to everyone in person.
跟大家道谢了
Please
请骆小姐
convey our gratitude
替我和华桢
on behalf of my brother and me.
跟大家说一声谢谢
Until we meet again.
后会有期
Young Master.
二少爷